SIMON WONG

Software Engineer & IT Professional

WORK EXPERIENCE

LifeBrand - West Chester, PA (Sep 2023 - Present)

Lead Software Engineer

Full-stack engineer focused on modernization, feature development, and SOC 2 compliance for an Al-driven social media cleaning startup. Helping individuals and businesses understand and build their social media brand using React, NextJS on Vercel, Node.js, GraphQL, AWS, and Google Cloud Platform.

LLUNA - Remote ET (Feb 2023 - Present)

Founding Software Engineer

Co-founder and full-stack engineer leading the buildout and modernization of an HR technology startup's core technology products: the Personal Operating Profile (POP) and TeamOS. Building software that connects people and teams using React, NextJS on Vercel, Node.js, Apollo, and Google Cloud Platform.

IKEA US DIGITAL HUB - Conshohocken, PA (Apr 2021 - Feb 2023)

Senior Software Engineer

Digital Shopping Experience - Conversion Funnel

Full-stack engineer supporting IKEA's global e-commerce products. Drove international customer conversion through innovative technical solutions and data-driven experimentation. Building, deploying, and scaling cloud-based micro-applications using React, Node.js, and Google Cloud Platform.

THE VANGUARD GROUP, INC - Malvern, PA (Jul 2015 - Apr 2021)

Software Engineering Chapter Lead

Retail Systems - Client Experience & Digital (Apr 2020 - Apr 2021)

EXTRACURRICULAR

THE VANGUARD GROUP, INC

Developer Experience Champion | Jan 2020 - Apr 2021 TechTalks Conference Lead | May 2016 - Mar 2020 Technology Leadership Program | Jul 2015 - Jul 2017

CHARLIE'S CRUSADERS PET RESCUE

Website Administrator | May 2018 - Present

PENN STATE IFC/PANHELLENIC DANCE MARATHON Technology Committee Captain | Apr 2014 - Mar 2015



ABOUT ME

I am a professional software engineer based out of the greater Philadelphia area with experience in technical leadership and full stack web development.

My passions include building beautiful software products with a client-centric lens, embracing the DevOps mindset, and crafting an engineering culture that celebrates inclusion and innovation.

EDUCATION

M.S.E. Software Engineering Penn State University '19

B.S. Information Sciences & Technology Penn State University '15

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End

- ▶ JavaScript, TypeScript
- ▶ React, Next.js, Angular, Sass
- ▶ Jest, React Testing Library, Playwright
- ▶ Optimizely Web & Full-Stack

Back-End

- ▶ Node.js, Express.js
- ► GraphQL, Apollo, urql
- ► Prisma, PostgreSQL

Operations & Infrastructure

- ▶ AWS, GCP, Vercel
- ► Sentry, Datadog, Splunk
- CI/CD Pipelines (Github Actions, Bamboo)

GET IN TOUCH



www.simonwong.dev



simonzwong



hello@simonwong.dev